What do you think, where is the highest standard of living,
Как ты считаешь где вышей уровень жизни
in Europe or in Russia, and in Russia the
в Европе или в России а в России выше
question is higher? If the standard of living is higher in Russia,
вопрос Если в России выше уровень жизни
why do I communicate with people from Estonia, they all have their
почему вот я общаюсь с людьми из Эстонии
teeth done, and I communicate with
у них у всех сделаны зубы а общаюсь с
people from Russia, they all have either gold
людьми из России У них всех либо золотые
or knocked out teeth, or it’s just trash,
либо выбитые либо там вообще траш
well, our teeth are expensive, I’m not here, SPO.
ну у нас зубы дела дорого я здесь не СПО
And
А
why?
почему Здравствуйте
Hello, I’m from the city of Khmelnitsky, where are you
Здравствуйте я из города Хмельницке Вы
from,
откуда
Vladivostok. It’s cool, it’s already morning,
Владивосток Прикольно у вас уже утро
probably not yet night, and what are you
наверное нет пока ещё ночь а чем
communicating with, I do
общаетесь
n’t know, I’m just looking for someone to talk to. How are you
не знаю просто ищу с кем поговорить Ваши
doing? Who to talk to? Well, talk to
дела С кем поговорить Ну говорите со
me. I usually ask people from Vladivostok
мной я вот у людей из Владивостока
for you in Russia.
обычно спрашиваю для вас в России
The United States - Who is a friend or enemy? Well, the
Соединённые Штаты - Это кто друг враг
average is most likely like a friend. An enemy or an enemy is a friend. Well,
кто Ну средняя скорее всего это как друг
as they
Враг или враг друг Ну вот вот как
said, it seems like a friend, but it seems like an
сказали вроде и друг а вроде и
enemy. Let’s still define it. Well, in the sense, the United States cannot be our enemy because they are
быть нашим врагом потому что мы им
interested in us in all areas, just
интересны во всех сферах так
as they cannot be enemies for us
так же как и они для нас не могут быть
because they are also interesting to
врагами потому что они тоже интересны
us in all areas. Well, this is purely my
нам во всех сферах Ну это чисто моё
opinion. I don’t  I
мнение Я не не
will not be for anyone And what about NATO expansion
буду ни за кого А как же расширение НАТО
And so
И так
on Well NATO expansion will not
дальше Ну расширение НАТО дальше не
go further because there is
пойдёт потому что там сейчас
Trump now Trump will now stop where they
Трамп Трамп сейчас остановится там где
said
сказали
I understand by the way I am 43 years old you are what 34 I
понял мне кстати 43 года тебе сколько 34
understand And what do you talk about
понял А чем общаешься
just about life Listen and this is what you
просто о жизни Слушай а вот такое ты кем
do for a living I
работаешь Я
work
работаю
this in short I check the quality of the
этим короче проверяю на качество
product can I have 5 seconds here
продукта можно 5 секунд вот
I am laughing at
яю да
us
нами хохочет ться
and in general I check the quality of Chinese products
а в общем я проверяю китайские продукты
you bite them I mean Well yes
качество кусаешь их В смысле
almost Well I mean they send me reports I
почти Ну в смысле мне присылают отчёты я
check them [music] more questions now you say Yes Hello Yes
проверяю ещё вопросы сейчас говоришь Да
speak Yeah Yes
Алло Да говори
you
вы рейми
see Reimi Well then everything from
видишь Ну всё тогда от
Reimi so well I don't know what to
рейми так вот ну я не знаю что тебе
tell you honestly
сказать честно
ask the question I will answer the question what do
задавай вопрос я буду отвечать вопрос
you think where is the highest standard of living
как ты считаешь где высший уровень жизни
in Europe or in
в Европе или в
Russia Well depending on which
России Ну смотря какой
Europe Let's go in Estonia or in
Европе Давай в Эстонии или в
Russia in Russia is higher question If the
России в России выше вопрос Если в
standard of living is higher in Russia why do I
России выше уровень жизни почему вот я
talk to people from Estonia they all have their
общаюсь людьми из Эстонии у них у всех
teeth made as with people from gold
сделаны зубы ась с людьми из ли золо
or knocked out or there is generally sh Well our
либо выбитые либо там вообще ш Ну у нас
teeth are expensive  I'm not a SPO here And
зубы дела дорого я здесь не СПО А
why because they cover it for
почему потому что они покрывают это
free
бесплатно
medicine I won't even argue here And
медицина я тут даже Спорить не буду А
how much does it cost to get teeth done in Russia
сколько в России стоит сделать
Well, I mean what
зубы Ну в смысле что
exactly
именно
uh can you do there like veneers for a
ээ можно сделать там как виниры за
million
миллион
uh can you do uh what's it called there
ээ можно сделать э как его там
And there one tooth when it's there
А там один зуб когда это там
58,000 to remove
58.000 удалить
there now 5 more seconds
там сейчас 5 секунд ещё
Hello in general getting
Алло в общем
teeth done is
зубы делать
expensive here I won't argue
дорого здесь я Спорить не
And what happened to your teeth Oh
буду А что с вашими зубами случилось А
yeah I got into a fight How
да подрался Как
long ago a month ago and in a month they put in
давно месяц назад и за месяц ставили
gold ones Yes, if they were
золотые Да если бы
gold There they are
золотые Вон
I don't Well, I mean what kind of gold
они я не Ну в смысле Какие золотые Вот
They are ordinary iron and iron Understand I would
они обычные железные а железные
gladly put in gold ones
Поня Я б с удовольствием бы золотые бы
Well, what's the point but they are
Ну а смысл а они же
soft Yes, what is the
мягкие Да
samber below which you
что самбер снизу который
take everything
сам бери
below everything come on come on I
внизу всё всё давай давай я
[music] now The
[музыка]
point is that Well, I put in my
сечас Суть в том то что Ну вот я вставил
front teeth for 30,000 rubles but they
передние но они
were to straighten my bite
их была в том то чтобы выровнять прикус
and in six months put in
и через полгода вставить
like normal teeth Yes,
типа нормальные зубы Да
damn Ask again Well,
блин Проси ещё
now I'm here these fell out and those  I'll insert Yes
я сейчас вот эти выпали и те вставлю
you
Да ты опять
called again Yes of course can I
звонил Да конечно можно мне зака
order an order
заказывать
no on
нет на
sava everything everything everything
саве всё всё всё
come on he too
давай он тоже
this kafan asks to order it for
это кафан просит это заказать
him
ему
what a taxi
что такси
Uh-huh And he can't order it himself And
Угу А он что не может сам заказать А у
he has what they say there is no money on the
него это как его там говорится денег на
phone
телефоне
how how how to get you back And
нету как как как вас обратно вернуть А
in all
во всё
[music]
[музыка]
how are you
у вас как
doing Yes I talk to people from Russia
дела Да я вот общаюсь с людьми из России
about politics and economics And what do you think
о политике и экономике А как ты считаешь
why is it that Russia with oil
почему вот всё-таки Россия с нефтью
gas gold diamonds and Such a rich
газом золотом алмазам и Такая богатейшая
country but with teeth
страна но с зубами вот недоступна
dentistry is inaccessible Yes in comparison with
стоматология Да в сравнении с Эстонии
small Estonia Well here I will tell you nothing I don't
маленькой Ну тут я вам ничего скажу я не
know how much it costs in Estonia to get
знаю сколько в Эстонии стоит
my teeth done my teeth cost 30,000
зубы мои зубы стоит сделать 30.000
rubles It's me Well one tooth or all teeth not
руб Это я Ну один зуб или все зубы не не
all 30,000 rubles Yes so that's 300
все 30.000 руб Да так это 300
dollars well for you 300 dollars is
долларов ну для вас 300 долларов - это
pennies so once again how many
копейки так ещё раз сколько там у вас
teeth do you have
зубов
I have four teeth 300
у меня четыре зуба 300
dollars well if in your opinion as you
долларов ну если по-вашему как вы
say that is you don't have  300,000 30
говорите то есть у вас нету 300000 30
30,000 rubles 300 dollars to
30.000 руб 300 долларов для того чтобы
make yourself a normal jaw I
сделать себе нормальную челюсть У меня
have them I
есть они у меня выпали
recently lost my teeth I mean I mean
недавно кто выпали зубы в смысле я имею
well 30,000 rubles You have to
в виду ну 30.000 руб У вас есть чтобы
make a
сделать
jaw like that but you won't
челюсть так а не
do it Well they're not
сделаете Ну они пока того не
worth it yet I recently took out a
стоят Я недавно взял это
mortgage for this I'm currently spending everything there that is it turns
ипотеку У меня сейчас уходит всё туда
out in Russia either a
а то есть получается в России либо
mortgage or
ипотека либо
teeth Well it's not that I can
зубы Ну не то чтобы не то чтобы я могу и
do both but I have
то и то сделать но у меня есть
priorities like well without teeth I'm the same
приоритеты как бы ну без зубов я тот же
person I was
человек который и был
and without an
а без
apartment it's already more
квартиры здесь уже
difficult here Well look It seems to me
сложнее Ну смотрите Мне кажется
uh if you take and in a month at least somewhere
ээ если взять и в месяц хотя бы где-то
additional work at least for 100
дополнительно подработок хотя бы на 100
dollars for 10,000 rubles in 3 months You can
долларов на 10.000 руб за 3 месяца Можно
collect for teeth Yes there you can even in a month
на зубки собрать Да там можно и за месяц
ate what Well it's possible in a month Well I do
ели что Ну так можно и за месяц Ну так я
n't believe that this problem is so
не верю что эта проблема такая
overwhelming
неподъёмная
Yes I agree Well I just don't need it I'll
Да согласен Ну просто мне оно не надо я
put them in as soon as I find time
как найдётся время так и поставлю их у
you have a wife a girl yes  how does she
вас жена девушка есть да как она
feel about your
относится к вашей
jaw Well, for now with
Челюсти Ну пока со
me Well, what does she even say Is
мной Ну что она вообще говорит Стоит ли
it worth doing it or not Well, in the sense Of course it is, so
её делать не стоит Не ну в смыс Конечно
do it Well, damn, I want to do it with my own money and
делаете Ну блин я хочу сделать за свои а
not hers
не за её
As they say Is it a girl or a
деньги Как говорится Это девушка или
wife,
жена
wife, wife Well, so if you pay the
жена жена Ну так если ты выплачивает
mortgage Well, so what's the problem that
ипотеку Ну так в чём проблема что с
part of her salary is used to get your teeth
части её зарплаты тебе зубы
done Well, my teeth don't interfere with housing Yes, I
сделать Ну мои зубы не мешают жилью Да я
understand, yes, but it
понял да но оно
interferes, as it were, and Your health, it
мешает как бы и Твоему здоровью это ж
affects your health later Yes, no, not at
влияет на здоровье потом Да нет вообще
all, it doesn't affect Well, I mean,
никак как никак не влияет Ну в смысле а
how can it affect health You won't
как оно может влиять на здоровье Ты не
believe how teeth affect health,
поверишь как зубы влияют на здоровье
firstly, and the gastrointestinal tract,
во-первых и на желудочно-кишечный тракт
and blood pressure, and in the head, in short, yes
и на давление и на в голове короче да
Where
Там где
you go differently, these are already strengthenings, yes,
ты по-другому идут уже это усиления да
somewhere there is
где-то давит
more pressure, which will move somewhere,
больше то что съедет куда-нибудь
yes Well, I agree here, I agree here, well, I'm
да Ну тут согласен тут согласен ну я-то
not going to walk with all this for so long And
не так долго собираюсь с этим всем
how long are you going to walk Yes,
ходить А сколько собираешься походить Да
a month or two and
месяц два и
[music] that's it and I'll
[музыка]
get myself normal
всё и поставлю себе нормальные
teeth Well, I agree with you, our teeth are incredibly
зубы Ну зубы я согласен У нас пипец
expensive And what's good is that in Russia it's
какие дорогие А что хорошо что в России
better than in
лучше чем в
Europe
Европе
[music]
[музыка]
pension in Russia pension is better than in
пенсия в России пенсия лучше чем в
Europe Well yes in Russia pension How much
Европе Ну да в России пенсия Сколько
now I don't know I most likely will not
сейчас не знаю я свою скорее всего не
see mine but so from 20 to 50,000 Where in
увижу но а так вот от 20 до 50.000 Где в
Russia is the minimum pension what is it 12,000 rubles
России минимальная пенсия что 12.000 руб
now the minimum here what is it called
сечас минимальная у нас как его
here we have minimum pension now now now
там у нас минимальные поро сейчас сейчас
22,000 rubles yes 22,000 minimum
сейчас 22.000 руб да 22000 минимальная
pension 220
пенсия 220
dollars we have minimum unemployment I
долларов у нас минималка безработиц
think now 18 Well I can't say for sure Yes
по-моему сейчас 18 Ну точно не скажу Да
you want to say that your pension is higher
ты хочешь сказать что у вас пенсия выше
than in Europe yes It's
чем в Европе да
not a fact that there is a pension at all And if you
Не факт что вообще пенсия есть И если ты
If you are fired from work then what is
если Тебя уволят с работы то какая у
your pension And here it is well how is it
тебя пенсия А у нас-то она ну как его
guaranteed
гарантированная
yes then maybe it is better to live in Europe And to
да то може лучше жить в Европе А на
move to
пенсию переезжать в
Russia on pension well I won't say here it doesn't seem to
Россию ну тут не скажу оно вроде так не
work
работает
like that you have to choose
типа ты должен выбрать какую-то
one And what about these pensioners in Europe
одну А что вот эти в Европе пенсионеры
who do not receive a pension how do they live
которые не получают пенсию как они живут
die on  streets or how Yes not ours yours ours
умирают на улицах или как Да не
As you
наши ваши наши Как вы
know live there and receive nu and
знаете живут там и получа ню и
look at me here the audience wants to ask
виду у меня вот зрители хотят позадавать
you questions Come on maybe I will
тебе вопросы Давай может я буду
read out the questions you will answer
зачитывать вопросы ты будешь отвечать
Come on Yes what is your name Mikhail Mikhail
Давай Да как тебя зовут Михаил Михаил
my name is Andrey so Maryan from Prague from the
меня Андрей так вот Марьян из Праги из
Czech Republic asks where have you been in Europe And have
Чехии спрашивает где ты был в Европе А в
not been to Europe only in China only
Европе не был был только в Китае только
in China so People Come on yes write
в Китае так Народ Давайте да пишите
questions in the chat we make an answer otherwise they
вопросы в чатик делаем ответ иначе так
write like this here anis writes in Latvia we have a
пишут вот анис пишет в Латвии у нас
minimum salary of 740 euros and do you
минимальная зарплата 740 евро и ты
really think that in Europe the
действительно думаешь что в Европе
pension is less than
пенсия
740 euros - This is a salary not a
меньше 740 евро - Это зарплата не пенсия
minimum pension but a minimum salary anes
минимальная а минимальная зарплата анес
Write a pension Write What is the minimum pension
Напишите пенсию Напишите Какая
in the country ka Each
минимальная пенсия в стране ка Каждый
write your country and the minimum
напишите свою страну и минимальная
pension What Oksana asks what is your
пенсия Какая Оксана спрашивает что ты по
education
образованию
I am a software engineer
Я как инженер-программист
Well I don't know if they have such a thing or not I
Ну я не знаю есть у них такое или нет
understood
понял
So on my own fought asks no no no no was not
Так на сво воевал спрашивает не не не
going to I am against the war
собирался Я против войны
Germany writes a pension of 1,600 euros minimum
Германия пишет пенсия 1.600 евро минимум
Lithuania pension  600-800
Литва пенсия 600-800
euros
евро
for a
на
pension they pay at this time for something
пенсия они платят в это время за что-то
else on top of that do they have discounts there on
ещё сверху есть у них скидки там на
electricity or And what else well on
электричество либо И что ж ещё что-то ну
utilities What discounts
на на коммунальные услуги Какие скидки
on electricity Listen in Europe
на электриче Слушай в Европе
electricity yes In general payments are generally
электричество да В общих платежах вообще
minimal How much do you pay for electricity
минимально Сколько ты за электричество
in a month as a couple of cups of
вообще в месяц платишь как пару чашек
coffee Well maybe maybe I won't say anything here
кофе Ну возможно возможно Тут ничего не
I haven't started
скажу я ещё не начинал
paying yet I just took out a mortgage on an apartment
платить Я только взял квартиру в ипотеку
Yeah and under What percentage did I take out a mortgage
Угу а под Какой процент взял в ипотеку
2% is this some kind of state
2% это это какая-то государственная
program yes for a young family
программа да для молодой семьи
[music]
[музыка]
Hello Yes everything everything everything will arrive soon I just
Алло Да всё всё всё скоро приедет я тебе
threw you 5 seconds
кинул 5 секун
96 Well
96 Ну
where Well
где Ну
I do
вот я
n't
не
know the question why people from Russia go
знаю вопрос почему люди из России едут
leave to live in Europe and vice versa don't
уезжают в Европу жить а наоборот не
leave because most likely
уезжают потому что скорее
only those
всего в Европу уезжают только те у
whose wives earn money in Europe leave for Europe
которых жёны зарабатывают в
I mean those
Европе В смысле в Европу уезжают Те у
whose wives earn money in Europe leave for Europe Well I
кого жёны зарабатывают в Европе Ну в
mean there are these what's their name
смысле есть эти как его там
deputies deputies have a certain
депутаты у депутатов есть определённая
salary and
зарплата
when they buy for themselves  some kind of how do
так и когда они покупают себе какие-то
they
там как о там
say Well, in general, the
говорится Ну в общем
wife bought the mansion with what she
хоромы это жена купила на то что она
earned, I
заработала
understand That is, it turns out that everyone who leaves for
понял То есть получается все кто уезжает
Europe is just uh, deputies who have
в Европу это просто ээ депутаты у
wives Well, in short, they are
жёны Ну короче это
horse thieves, I
конокрады
understand
понял
Yes, I won’t even argue here,
Да тут я даже Спорить не буду даже
people have even run out of questions
вопросы у людей
because embezzlers are
закончились потому что казнокрады они
everywhere,
есть везде
okay Let’s go Then he’s really
ладно Давай пойдём Дальше он реально
some kind of shi on Instagram I don’t know why this is for
какой-то ши на й Instagram Я не знаю для
you, why else would you look
чого це тоб для чого ще тоб там дивитись
at this face and for you, one, two or three
на оцей фейс а для тебе оди два або три
clicks But you try me and I’ll be there There are
клика Але ты тримае мене и я буду к в
a bunch of fouls and I’ll have a cool
мене там Купа фолов и ме буде класный
nayb Robbie, but a cool video letter on
найб Роби но крут вдео пись на й
Instagram Andriy, that’s
Instagram к Андрий вот
it, let’s wait for you
так давай я тебя чекаю